<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on VDLH Portfolio</title><link>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on VDLH Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/basecase-demo-apps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/basecase-demo-apps/</guid><description>BaseCase Demo Apps # 2019, Berlin
Client # BaseCase GmbH # BaseCase is a drag-and-drop platform to create interactive online content. With BaseCase the user is able to integrate UI elements and realize dynamic calculations on the screen. Role # As UX/UI Designer I contributed to this project being responsible for the design and implementation of a line of demos that built the BaseCase Demo Apps Library. This library was a collection of demos are interactive presentations that showcase the capabilities of the BaseCase platform as a data visualization tool.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/bella-vista-video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/bella-vista-video/</guid><description>Bella Vista Video # 2016, Berlin
Bella Vista is the name of a humble fisherman area in the southeast coast of Isla Margarita. In this area of the island I lived and grew up with my parents and my two siblings. Living on a 7th floor apartment in a building located almost at the middle of Bella Vista Beach, gave us an ample view of the Guaraguao’s Bay. Here we were able to see the sea everyday just by looking through any of the windows pointing south or by walking through the terraces.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/creators-search-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/creators-search-tool/</guid><description> Creators Search Tool # 2021, Berlin
Client # The Creator&amp;rsquo;s Search Tool was intended to be an internal tool used by the Production Team at Talenthouse. Brief # To facilitate the search of talent..</description></item><item><title/><link>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/eyeems-checkout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/eyeems-checkout/</guid><description>EyeEm&amp;rsquo;s Checkout Process Redesign # 2023, Berlin
Client # &amp;ldquo;EyeEm is a global photography community and marketplace. We connect our engaged creators with leading brands to provide original, unique and on-brand content. Our mission is to empower our community by offering them a platform to get discovered, while giving brands access to the most powerful creative imagery worldwide.&amp;rdquo;
https://www.eyeem.com/story Brief # In 2023, EyeEm re-vamped the Checkout Process Redesign project with the scope of offering the buyer users a new experience while performing a purchase.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/make-city/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/make-city/</guid><description>Make City # 2015, Berlin
Make City Festival / Make_Shift gGmbH (c) Verónica De León Hernández
On June 2015 I volunteered as a photographer in the Make City Festival in Berlin to document some of their events.
MAKE CITY is Berlin’s first festival for architecture and urban alternatives, bringing together architects, planners, civic groups and developers in a citywide conversation on thinking and making city differently.
Make City&amp;rsquo;s Website For more images of the festival visit their Flickr page:</description></item><item><title/><link>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/pong-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/pong-game/</guid><description>PONG GAME # 2020, Berlin
Github: https://github.com/veronicadeleonh/pong-game
Role # As a UX/UI Designer and Web Developer of this product, I have recreated the look and feel of arcade games to build my own version of the PONG game. Relying on online documentation, I used vanilla JavaScript and P5.js to code the functionalities of the game and CSS to implement the UI. Brief # I wanted to create a two players experience where the users could enter their games to record the score before starting the match.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/roma-pride-2010/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://veronicadeleon.de/docs/roma-pride-2010/</guid><description>Roma Pride 2010 # 2010, Rome
This LGBTQ+ event on July 2010 in Rome, filled the streets with the happy vibe from all its attenders. This unique and contagious spirit starred the evening, encouraging everyone into a collective feeling of self-acceptance and sharing. This celebration of love and acceptance impulsed us all to share our best smile.
This set of Photographs took part on
Espo Arti in Fieri 2010, Punto Estatico.</description></item></channel></rss>