<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Projects on Verónica De León Hernández</title><link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Verónica De León Hernández</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mondly</title><link>http://localhost:1313/mondly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/mondly/</guid><description>My role at Mondly involved a variety of tasks, collaborating closely with designers, marketers, User Acquisition and Growth specialists, website developers, and data scientists to consolidate Mondly&amp;rsquo;s rebrand across all touchpoints.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="intro-info">
<p><span class="tag blue text-blue">e-learning</span></p>
<p class="intro-description">My role at Mondly involved a variety of tasks, collaborating closely with designers, marketers, User Acquisition and Growth specialists, website developers, and data scientists to consolidate Mondly's rebrand across all touchpoints.</p>
  <div class="intro-details-wrapper">
      <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/mouse.svg)"></span> Senior Product Designer</p>
      <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/globe.svg)"></span> Fully remote</p>
      <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/calendar.svg)"></span>  2023 - 2024</p>
  </div>
</div>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/mondly/images/mondly-intro.jpg" type="" alt="Mondly"  /></p>
<h3 id="about-mondly">About Mondly</h3>
<p><strong>Mondly</strong> is a language learning app that aims to make language learning fun and easy through technological innovation and multiple language combinations.</p>
<p>On 2022 Mondly got acquired by Pearson, giving the Product team a chance for a big redesign of Mondly&rsquo;s platform and web presence.</p>
<h3 id="my-role-at-mondly">My Role at Mondly</h3>
<p>During my stay at Mondly, making <strong>A/B tests</strong> about the performance of the Old vs. the New Design was important to validate with data the development of the rebrand and plan the marketing strategies for this design transition.</p>
<p>Before I joined the team, the product designers put in place a detailed <strong>design system</strong> that served as base for all the future assets we developed on the way. I collaborated closely with one of my colleagues on the creation of a <strong>style guide</strong> in Notion, were we documented the details of the New Mondly Brand and its usage.</p>
<a href="images/styleguide-components.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/styleguide-components.png" alt="Mondly Style Guide Components">
</a>
<p class="photo-footnote">View of some of the components built for the Styleguide in Figma</p>
<h3 id="mondly-web--marketing">Mondly Web &amp; Marketing</h3>
<p>With a major rebranding underway, we created brand guidelines based on our design system that we could extend into marketing materials. We conducted a series of <strong>A/B tests</strong> to compare the performance of the <strong>new design versus the old one</strong>, ensuring a positive impact on user engagement.</p>
<h4 id="redesigned-offer-page">Redesigned Offer page</h4>
<p>For this project, we adapted the app’s design system for use on a marketing landing page for the first time. This laid the foundation for a <strong>scalable design system</strong> tailored to <strong>web marketing materials</strong>, evolving with the team’s needs. It also enabled us to expand the style guide specifically for marketing designers, who would use it in areas such as social media campaign ideation.</p>
<p>If curious, here is <a href="https://www.mondly.com/offer/lifetime-en?avangate_src=src-go-brand-ww-en-exact-bf24" target="\_blank">Mondly&rsquo;s Offer page with Old design<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></a> for comparison.</p>
<a href="images/mondly-offer-page.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/mondly-offer-page.png" alt="Mondly Offer Page">
</a>
<p class="photo-footnote">Preview of the Offer Page redesign on iPad mini and iPhone SE</p>
<div class="box-notes yellow-background" style="margin-bottom:20px">
 The redesigned Offer page resulted in an increase in <strong>average time on page</strong> and a lower <strong>bounce rate</strong> compared to the original control version.</div>
<h4 id="app-store--google-play-images">App Store &amp; Google Play images</h4>
<p>In order to test the impact of the rebranding on the Stores, we initiated a project to extend the new brand to these images. The light mode was introduced after benchmarking research showed competitors favoring light backgrounds in their App Store images. We organized several <strong>Design Team workshops</strong> to develop a light version of our new brand, allowing us to include it in the <strong>A/B testing.</strong></p>
 <a href="images/app-store-images-dark.png" class="lightbox">
   <img src="images/app-store-images-dark.png" alt="Mondly App Store Images Dark Theme">
 </a>
 <a href="images/app-store-images-light.png" class="lightbox">
   <img src="images/app-store-images-light.png" alt="Mondly App Strore Images Light Theme">
 </a>
<p class="photo-footnote">Screenshots of the dark and light versions of the App Store images for iPhone X</p>
<div class="box-notes yellow-background" style="margin-bottom:20px"> Data showed a <strong>nearly 3% increase in App Store downloads</strong> with <strong>Mondly's Light theme</strong> version compared to the control and dark theme variants. With this percentage we met our OKRs for Q1 2024</div>
<h3 id="mondly-growth--monetization">Mondly Growth &amp; Monetization</h3>
<p>The Growth team initiated several <strong>A/B tests</strong> to <strong>increase Premium Subscriptions</strong>. We tested various strategies, including designing new banners, creating templates for seasonal campaigns, and making UX improvements to the Free Trial screen.</p>
<a href="images/mondly-lto.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/mondly-lto.png" alt="Mondly LTO">
</a>
<p class="photo-footnote">Preview of the Limited Time Offer Banner variants for testing</p>
<h4 id="seasonal-campaigns">Seasonal Campaigns</h4>
<p>Our user acquisition strategy used full-screen in-app ads to guide Free Trial users to the Subscription screen, offering them the opportunity to <strong>activate a Premium account</strong>.</p>
<a href="images/seasonal-campaigns-user-flow.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/seasonal-campaigns-user-flow.png" alt="Mondly User Flow Seasonal Campaign">
</a>
<p class="photo-footnote">User conversion through in-app ads flow</p>
<p>Our strategy used a default ad layout for all free users, which we then <strong>customized for each seasonal sale</strong>. This approach allowed us to create a flexible template, easily adapting key elements like colors and imagery to fit the seasonal theme.</p>
<a href="images/seasonal-campaigns-redesign.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/seasonal-campaigns-redesign.png" alt="Mondly Seasonal Campaign">
</a>
<p class="photo-footnote">In-app ad layout created for the Spring Campaign. Images generated with Midjourney</p>
<p>For the <strong>Spring Campaign 2024</strong>, we developed a new layout for the in-app ad and proposed two different background images. We launched both variants and conducted an <strong>A/B/C test</strong> alongside the current fallback.</p>
<a href="images/seasonal-campaigns-test-result.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/seasonal-campaigns-test-result.png" alt="Mondly Seasonal Campaign Results">
</a>
<div class="box-notes yellow-background" style="margin-bottom:20px">
 Results showed a slight increase of <strong>7% more 'Activate' taps</strong> with <strong>variant B performing better</strong>. Nearly <strong>2% of users</strong> who reached the Subscription screen proceeded with the<strong> App Store Drawer,</strong> moving further down the conversion funnel.
</div>
<h3 id="marketing-campaigns">Marketing Campaigns</h3>
<p>One major ongoing marketing campaign involved creating an onboarding flow with a questionnaire that guided users to a payment screen. I was responsible for the design and UX of this flow. The biggest challenge was developing a style that seamlessly blended elements of both the old and new Mondly branding.</p>
<a href="images/w2w-screens.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/w2w-screens.png" alt="Mondly W2W Screens">
</a>
<a href="images/w2w-components.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/w2w-components.png" alt="Mondly W2W Screens">
</a>
<p class="photo-footnote">Figma screenshot from the W2W campaing mockups and components in Figma</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>EyeEm</title><link>http://localhost:1313/eyeem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/eyeem/</guid><description>I worked in EyeEm for 2+ years, contributing on the brower-based platform, owning the Webflow account and helping with the recruitment of new designers to build a new Product Design Team.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="intro-info">
<p><span class="tag green text-green">e-commerce</span></p>
<p class="intro-description">I worked in EyeEm for 2+ years, contributing on the brower-based platform, owning the Webflow account and helping with the recruitment of new designers to build a new Product Design Team.</p>
  <div class="intro-details-wrapper">
    <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/mouse.svg)"></span> Product Designer</p>
    <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/location.svg)"></span> Berlin, Hybrid</p>
    <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/calendar.svg)"></span> 2021 - 2023</p>
  </div>
</div>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-intro.jpg" type="" alt="EyeEm"  /></p>
<h3 id="about-eyeem">About EyeEm</h3>
<p><strong>EyeEm</strong> is as a photography community and marketplace that facilitates connections between creators and prominent brands to source original and on-brand content.</p>
<h3 id="my-role-at-eyeem">My role at EyeEm</h3>
<p>During my role at EyeEm I was one of Designers inside the Product team, specifically collaborating on the maintenance of the browser-based application.</p>
<h3 id="how-we-worked">How we worked</h3>
<p>Our Product Design team collaborated closely with project managers, data analysts, and developers. We worked together on the continuos development of the platform and set up regular meetings and feedback sessions.</p>
<p>For the redesign of the Cart &amp; Checkout process, we analyzed <strong>data reports</strong>, identified <strong>pain points</strong>, elaborated hypothesis and proposed improvements. This included addressing UX improvements on the cart dropdown feature, background color inconsistencies, premature tax calculations, and issues with SSO implementation for logged-out users. We also collaborated with the legal team to ensure compliance with changes like pre-saving billing information and payment details.</p>
<a href="images/eyeem-user-flow.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/eyeem-user-flow.png" alt="EyeEm User Flow">
</a>
<p class="photo-footnote">Identifying Data take-aways and UI pain points on the Cart & Checkout flow</p>
<h3 id="ux-exploration">UX Exploration</h3>
<h4 id="cart-page">Cart Page</h4>
<a href="images/eyeem-ux-cart.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/eyeem-ux-cart.png" alt="EyeEm UX Cart">
</a>
<div class="box-notes yellow" style="margin-bottom:20px">With a <strong>60% drop-off rate</strong> among <strong>logged-out users</strong> before reaching the authentication step, we wanted to identify the main pain points on the Cart page.</div>
<h5 id="top-navigation">Top Navigation</h5>
<p>The Cart page <strong>lacked EyeEm&rsquo;s familiar top navigation</strong>, which could make users feel as though they’d left our site, potentially impacting trust. We hypothesized that reintroducing the top navigation might improve user confidence and retention.</p>
<h5 id="vat-calculations">VAT Calculations</h5>
<p>VAT calculations were appearing <strong>too early in the cart flow</strong>. As users added more items, the displayed total rose significantly, which might discourage them. We considered moving VAT calculations closer to the payment step to present a more approachable total earlier in the process.</p>
<h5 id="dark-theme-vs-light-theme">Dark Theme vs. Light Theme</h5>
<p>Based on research, we applied EyeEm’s dark theme to the Cart Page, along with the top navigation, to <strong>maintain visual consistency</strong> and keep users feeling connected to the platform. A light theme at this stage could have disrupted the flow, making users feel like they were leaving the page.</p>
<h4 id="authentication-for-logged-out-users">Authentication for logged out users</h4>
<a href="images/eyeem-ux-auth.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/eyeem-ux-auth.png" alt="EyeEm UX Authentication for logged out users">
</a>
<div class="box-notes yellow" style="margin-bottom:20px"><strong>Approximately 15% of users were dropping off</strong> on the Authentication screen. We required logged-out users to log in or create an account before proceeding, but this interruption often disrupted their flow.</div>
<h5 id="authentication-modal">Authentication Modal</h5>
<p>To create a more seamless experience, we moved authentication to a modal, <strong>allowing users to keep their Cart in view</strong> while logging in or signing up.</p>
<h5 id="ux-writing">UX writing</h5>
<p>To keep users engaged, we explored updating our UX copy with <strong>clearer instructions</strong>, gently reminding users they were in the middle of a purchase.</p>
<h5 id="guest-checkout-long-term-goals">Guest Checkout: Long-term goals</h5>
<p>We also discussed the potential for a Guest Checkout, allowing users to <strong>skip authentication until later stages</strong>. While this feature wasn’t implemented in this iteration, it remains a consideration for the future.</p>
<h4 id="checkout-page">Checkout Page</h4>
<a href="images/eyeem-ux-checkout.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/eyeem-ux-checkout.png" alt="EyeEm UX Checkput Page">
</a>
<div class="box-notes yellow" style="margin-bottom:20px"><strong>Only 10% of users</strong> who reached the Checkout page <strong>completed their purchase</strong>, highlighting a need to streamline this stage. We aimed to compress the steps required and reduce user interactions.</div>
<h5 id="cart-preview-pay-now--one-click-paypal-payment">Cart Preview, Pay Now &amp; One-click Paypal payment</h5>
<p>Previously, the &ldquo;Pay Now&rdquo; action was hidden in the second step and often inaccessible with longer Cart lists. We <strong>standardized the Cart preview</strong> by grouping items by license type, which kept the &ldquo;Pay Now&rdquo; and one-click PayPal options in view, encouraging <strong>quicker decision-making</strong>.</p>
<h5 id="optional-billing-info">Optional billing info</h5>
<p>Since our product <strong>didn’t require a shipping address</strong> and billing details were often unnecessary for users paying with PayPal, we considered making these fields optional to streamline the checkout experience.</p>
<h5 id="transfer-licensing-ongoing-discussion">Transfer Licensing: Ongoing discussion</h5>
<p>Many of our users—often designers or agencies buying for clients—needed an option to transfer licensing directly to their clients. Previously, they had to call Support to complete this transaction. By adding this feature to the redesign, we <strong>streamlined the process</strong> and responded to a frequent user need.</p>
<h5 id="pre-save-payment-and-billing-information-long-term-goals">Pre-save payment and billing information: Long term goals</h5>
<p>To streamline the purchase process, we considered <strong>pre-saving user data</strong>, such as cart details and billing information. However, due to capacity and alignment with the legal team, we decided to prioritize this feature for future iterations</p>
<h5 id="introducing-more-payment-methods-long-term-goals">Introducing more payment methods: Long term goals</h5>
<p>To enhance convenience, we considered adding <strong>more one-click payment options</strong>, such as Apple Pay and Google Pay, in future iterations.</p>
<div style="display:none">
### Low-fi & Prototype
<p>We created initial <strong>prototypes</strong> and discussed them with the Data and Front-End teams. Their feedback was crucial in finalizing a solution that addressed our quick wins.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.figma.com/proto/8uY2K7IVQ9ZY0zZ6nbfgLY/Cart-%26-Checkout-process-(Quick-wins)-(Copy)?page-id=2754%3A8279&node-id=2767-16673&viewport=831%2C395%2C0.06&t=CbdfJQfKEAJWeuO0-1&scaling=min-zoom&starting-point-node-id=2767%3A16673&show-proto-sidebar=1
" target="_blank" style="display:none">Check final prototype<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></a></p>
<a href="images/eyeem-low-fi-dropdown.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/eyeem-low-fi-dropdown.png" alt="Checkout Prototyping phase">
</a>
<p class="photo-footnote">Prototyping the new behaviour of the cart dopdown</p>
</div>
<h3 id="hi-fi--redesigned-screens">Hi-fi &amp; Redesigned screens</h3>
<p>The final step involved preparing high-fidelity mockups using our <strong>design system</strong>, ensuring consistency across the platform and alignment with the front-end developers&rsquo; UI kit.</p>
<a href="images/eyeem-auth.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/eyeem-auth.png" alt="EyeEm Hifi Authentication">
</a>
<a href="images/eyeem-hifi-modals.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/eyeem-hifi-modals.png" alt="EyeEm Hifi Modals">
</a>
<a href="images/eyeem-hifi-1.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/eyeem-hifi-1.png" alt="EyeEm Hifi Screens">
</a>
<a href="images/eyeem-hifi-2.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/eyeem-hifi-2.png" alt="EyeEm Hifi Screens">
</a>
<p class="photo-footnote">View of redesigned elements and screens</p>
<h3 id="eyeems-web-presence">EyeEm&rsquo;s Web presence</h3>
<p><a href="https://eyeem.com" target="_blank">EyeEm.com <span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></a> combines the flexibility of <strong>Webflow</strong> with the capabilities of front-end development, giving designers complete control over the UI and behavior of some areas of the website. I maintained various site areas and frequently launched landing pages for marketing campaigns, collaborating with the Marketing and Innovation teams. I was responsible for ideation, design, implementation, and final release of these projects.</p>
<p>Here are some live examples:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-web.jpg" type="" alt="EyeEm Web"  />
<a href="https://eyeem.com" target="\_blank">eyeem.com<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-magazine.jpg" type="" alt="EyeEm Web"  />
<a href="https://www.eyeem.com/magazine" target="_blank">eyeem.com/magazine<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></p></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-awards.jpg" type="" alt="EyeEm Web"  />
<a href="https://www.eyeem.com/awards" target="\_blank">eyeem.com/awards<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></p></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-creative-trends.jpg" type="" alt="EyeEm Web"  />
<a href="https://creativetrends.eyeem.com/" target="\_blank">creativetrends.eyeem.com<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></p></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>BaseCase</title><link>http://localhost:1313/basecase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/basecase/</guid><description>My first role at BaseCase started designing for web and Marketing but quickly transitioned into having a majority of UXUI tasks. Our small Design team worked closely to developers and copywriters on the client-facing documentation of the platform.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="intro-info">
<p><span class="tag orange text-orange">SaaS</span></p>
<p class="intro-description">My first role at BaseCase started designing for web and Marketing but quickly transitioned into having a majority of UXUI tasks. Our small Design team worked closely to developers and copywriters on the client-facing documentation of the platform.</p>
  <div class="intro-details-wrapper">
    <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/mouse.svg)"></span> UX/UI Designer</p>
    <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/location.svg)"></span> Berlin</p>
    <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/calendar.svg)"></span> 2017 - 2020</p>
  </div>
</div>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/basecase/images/basecase-intro.jpg" type="" alt="BaseCase"  /></p>
<h4 id="about-basecase">About BaseCase</h4>
<p><strong>BaseCase</strong> is a no-code platform that allows the users to translate spreadsheets into interactive &amp; data-driven content, tailored for the healthcare and medical science business.</p>
<h4 id="my-role-at-basecase">My role at Basecase</h4>
<p>My collaboration began with assisting the Marketing team on the design of digital and physical brochures, along with the necessary images for the web and recurring social media campaigns. After expressing interest in building my own BaseCase apps, I became involved in the production of client-facing tools and responsible for the BaseCase Apps Library.</p>
<h4 id="the-demo-app-library">The Demo App Library</h4>
<a href="images/demo-apps.jpg" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/demo-apps.jpg" alt="BaseCase Demo Apps Library">
</a>
<p>This library was a collection of tools that supported BaseCase documentation, illustrating everything from basic functionalities to complex features, along with product updates and use case tutorials. I was fully responsible for the ideation, design (or redesign), and implementation of these tools.</p>
<hr>
<a href="images/bc-demo-apps-brief.svg" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/bc-demo-apps-brief.svg" alt="BaseCase Demo Apps Brief">
</a>
<hr>
<p><strong style="text-transform: uppercase">Process creating the tools</strong></p>
<div class="numbering">
  <div class="numbers">1</div><span class="numbers-label">Identifying the scope and usage of the demo based on brief</span>
</div>
<div class="numbering">
  <div class="numbers">2</div><span class="numbers-label">Create low-fi mockups in Sketch and put all the ideation into place</span>
</div>
<div class="numbering">
  <div class="numbers">3</div><span class="numbers-label">Create an imaginary healthcare brand, choosing colors, fonts and logo</span>
</div>
<div class="numbering">
  <div class="numbers">4</div><span class="numbers-label">Implement the design and functionalities using the BaseCase platform</span>
</div>
<div class="numbering">
  <div class="numbers">5</div><span class="numbers-label">Test the app internally ensuring its full performance</span>
</div>
<div class="numbering">
  <div class="numbers">6</div><span class="numbers-label">Send the tool to QA</span>
</div>
<hr>
<a href="images/basecase-detailed-demo.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/basecase-detailed-demo.png" alt="Basecase Demo Apps">
</a>
<p class="photo-footnote">Close-ups to some of the tools that made part of the Demo App Library</p>
<h4 id="marketing-assets">Marketing Assets</h4>
<p>To support BaseCase&rsquo;s online presence, we developed a series of images for marketing campaigns, ranging from new feature launches to company participation in fairs. I was also responsible for creating images for the BaseCase website, many of which are still live under each category on <a href="https://basecase.com/features" target="_blank">BaseCase Features<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></a> page.</p>
<a href="images/basecase-features.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/basecase-features.png" alt="BaseCase Features">
</a>
<div style="display:none">
<a href="images/basecase-content-creation.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/basecase-content-creation.png" alt="BaseCase Features Content Creation">
</a>
<a href="images/basecase-spreadsheets.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/basecase-features-spreadsheets.png" alt="BaseCase Features Spreadsheets">
</a>
<a href="images/basecase-knowledge-base.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/basecase-knowledge-base.png" alt="BaseCase Features Knowledge Base">
</a>
<a href="images/basecase-success.png" class="lightbox">
  <img src="images/basecase-success.png" alt="BaseCase Features Success">
</a>
</div>
<p class="photo-footnote">Example of some of the Feature illustrations created for BaseCase's website</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>