<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Verónica De León Hernández</title><link>http://localhost:1313/</link><description>Recent content on Verónica De León Hernández</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mondly</title><link>http://localhost:1313/mondly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/mondly/</guid><description>My role at Mondly involved a variety of tasks, collaborating closely with designers, marketers, User Acquisition and Growth specialists, website developers, and data scientists to consolidate Mondly&amp;rsquo;s rebrand across all touchpoints.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="intro-info">
<p class="intro-description">My role at Mondly involved a variety of tasks, collaborating closely with designers, marketers, User Acquisition and Growth specialists, website developers, and data scientists to consolidate Mondly's rebrand across all touchpoints.</p>
  <div class="intro-details-wrapper">
      <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/mouse.svg)"></span> Senior Product Designer</p>
      <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/globe.svg)"></span> Full remote</p>
      <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/calendar.svg)"></span>  2023 - 2024</p>
  </div>
</div>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/mondly/images/mondly-intro.jpg" type="" alt="Mondly"  /></p>
<h3 id="about-mondly">About Mondly</h3>
<p><strong>Mondly</strong> is a language learning app that aims to make language learning fun and easy through technological innovation and multiple lanaguage combinations.</p>
<p>On 2022 Mondly got acquired by Pearson, giving the Product team a chance for a big redesign of Mondly&rsquo;s platform and web presence.</p>
<h3 id="my-role-at-mondly">My Role at Mondly</h3>
<p>During my stay at Mondly, making <strong>A/B tests</strong> about the performance of the Old vs. the New Design was important to validate with data the development of the rebrand and plan the marketing strategies for this design transition.</p>
<p>Before I joined the team, the product designers put in place a detailed <strong>design system</strong> that served as base for all the future assets we developed on the way. I collaborated closely with one of my colleagues on the creation of a <strong>style guide</strong> in Notion, were we documented the details of the New Mondly Brand and its usage.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/mondly/images/styleguide-components.png" type="" alt="Offer page"  /></p>
<p class="photo-footnote">View of some of the components built for the Styleguide in Figma</p>
<h3 id="mondly-web--marketing">Mondly Web &amp; Marketing</h3>
<p>Some of the tests we made included the redesign of the Offer page and the App and Google Store images, resulting on a increase of average time on page and the unique pageviews on the Offer page, and an <strong>increase of almost 3% of App Store downloads</strong> with Mondly&rsquo;s dark theme version, meeting our team OKR&rsquo;s for Q1 in 2024.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/mondly/images/mondly-offer-page.png" type="" alt="Offer page"  /></p>
<p class="photo-footnote">Glimpse to the Offer Page redesign</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/mondly/images/app-store-images-dark.png" type="" alt="App Store Images"  />
<img loading="lazy" src="/mondly/images/app-store-images-light.png" type="" alt="App Store Images"  /></p>
<p class="photo-footnote">Screenshot from the light and dark version of the App Store images for iPhone 10</p>
<div class="box-notes orange">
  Light mode was introduced after a benchmark research that showed competitors choosing light backgrounds on their app store images. We organized several <strong>Design Team workshops</strong> to develop a light version of our new brand, that we could include on the A/B testing.
</div>
<h3 id="mondly-growth">Mondly Growth</h3>
<p>The Growth team initiated several <strong>A/B tests</strong> aimed at increasing Premium Subscriptions. We tested various strategies, including designing new banners, creating templates for seasonal campaigns, and making UX improvements to the Free Trial screen.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/mondly/images/seasonal-campaigns.png" type="" alt="Seasonal Promos"  /></p>
<p class="photo-footnote">New layout for the in-app ads created for the Spring Campaign. Both versions were the subject of an A/B test on the background images. The images were generated using Midjourney.</p>
<h3 id="marketing-campaigns">Marketing Campaigns</h3>
<p>One major ongoing marketing campaign involved creating an onboarding flow with a questionnaire that guided users to a payment screen. I was responsible for the design and UX of this flow. The biggest challenge was developing a style that seamlessly blended elements of both the old and new Mondly branding.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/mondly/images/w2w-screens.png" type="" alt="W2W Screens"  />
<img loading="lazy" src="/mondly/images/w2w-components.png" type="" alt="W2W Screens"  /></p>
<p class="photo-footnote">Figma screenshot from the W2W campaing mockups and components in Figma</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>EyeEm</title><link>http://localhost:1313/eyeem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/eyeem/</guid><description>I worked in EyeEm for 2+ years, contributing on the brower-based platform, owning the Webflow account and helping with the recruitment of new designers to build a new Product Design Team.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="intro-info">
<p class="intro-description">I worked in EyeEm for 2+ years, contributing on the brower-based platform, owning the Webflow account and helping with the recruitment of new designers to build a new Product Design Team.</p>
  <div class="intro-details-wrapper">
    <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/mouse.svg)"></span> Product Designer</p>
    <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/location.svg)"></span> Berlin, Hybrid</p>
    <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/calendar.svg)"></span> 2021 - 2023</p>
  </div>
</div>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-intro.jpg" type="" alt="EyeEm"  /></p>
<h4 id="about-eyeem">About EyeEm</h4>
<p><strong>EyeEm</strong> is as a photography community and marketplace that facilitates connections between creators and prominent brands to source original and on-brand content.</p>
<h4 id="my-role-at-eyeem">My role at EyeEm</h4>
<p>During my role at EyeEm I was one of Designers inside the Product team, specifically collaborating on the maintenance of the browser-based application.</p>
<h4 id="how-we-worked">How we worked</h4>
<p>Our Product Design team collaborated closely with project managers, data analysts, and developers. We worked together on the continuos development of the platform and set up regular meetings and feedback sessions.</p>
<p>For the redesign of the Cart &amp; Checkout process, I analyzed <strong>data reports</strong>, identified <strong>pain points</strong>, elaborated hypothesis and proposed improvements. This included addressing UX improvements on the cart dropdown feature, background color inconsistencies, remature tax calculations, and issues with SSO implementation for logged-out users. I also collaborated with the legal team to ensure compliance with changes like pre-saving billing information and payment details.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-user-flow.png" type="" alt="EyeEm Hi-fi"  /></p>
<p class="photo-footnote">Identifying Data take-aways and UI pain points on the Cart & Checkout flow</p>
<h4 id="low-fi--prototype">Low-fi &amp; Prototype</h4>
<p>I created initial <strong>prototypes</strong> and discussed them with the Data and Front-End teams. Their feedback was crucial in finalizing a solution that addressed our quick wins.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.figma.com/proto/8uY2K7IVQ9ZY0zZ6nbfgLY/Cart-%26-Checkout-process-(Quick-wins)-(Copy)?page-id=2754%3A8279&node-id=2767-16673&viewport=831%2C395%2C0.06&t=CbdfJQfKEAJWeuO0-1&scaling=min-zoom&starting-point-node-id=2767%3A16673&show-proto-sidebar=1
" target="_blank" style="display:none">Check final prototype<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-low-fi-dropdown.png" type="" alt="Checkout Prototyping phase"  /></p>
<p class="photo-footnote">Prototyping the new behaviour of the cart dopdown</p>
<h4 id="hi-fi--redesigned-screens">Hi-fi &amp; Redesigned screens</h4>
<p>The final step involved preparing high-fidelity mockups using our <strong>design system</strong>, ensuring consistency across the platform and alignment with the front-end developers&rsquo; UI kit.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-auth.png" type="" alt="EyeEm Hi-fi"  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-hifi-modals.png" type="" alt="EyeEm Hi-fi"  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-hifi.png" type="" alt="EyeEm Hi-fi"  /></p>
<p class="photo-footnote">Glimpse to redesigned elements and screens</p>
<h4 id="eyeems-web-presence">EyeEm&rsquo;s Web presence</h4>
<p><a href="http://eyeem.com" target="_blank">EyeEm.com <span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></a> combines the flexibility of <strong>Webflow</strong> with the capabilities of front-end development, giving designers complete control over the UI and behavior of some areas of the website. I maintained various site areas and frequently launched landing pages for marketing campaigns, collaborating with the Marketing and Innovation teams. I was responsible for ideation, design, implementation, and final release of these projects.</p>
<p>Here are some live examples:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-web.jpg" type="" alt="EyeEm Web"  />
<a href="http://eyeem.com" target="\_blank">eyeem.com<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-magazine.jpg" type="" alt="EyeEm Web"  />
<a href="https://www.eyeem.com/magazine" target="_blank">eyeem.com/magazine<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></p></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-awards.jpg" type="" alt="EyeEm Web"  />
<a href="https://www.eyeem.com/awards" target="\_blank">eyeem.com/awards<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></p></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/eyeem/images/eyeem-creative-trends.jpg" type="" alt="EyeEm Web"  />
<a href="https://creativetrends.eyeem.com/" target="\_blank">creativetrends.eyeem.com<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></p></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>BaseCase</title><link>http://localhost:1313/basecase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/basecase/</guid><description>My first role at BaseCase started designing for web and Marketing but quickly transitioned into having a majority of UXUI tasks. Our small Design team worked closely to developers and copywriters on the client-facing documentation of the platform.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="intro-info">
<p class="intro-description">My first role at BaseCase started designing for web and Marketing but quickly transitioned into having a majority of UXUI tasks. Our small Design team worked closely to developers and copywriters on the client-facing documentation of the platform.</p>
  <div class="intro-details-wrapper">
    <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/mouse.svg)"></span> UX/UI Designer</p>
    <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/location.svg)"></span> Berlin</p>
    <p class="intro-details no-margin-bottom"><span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/calendar.svg)"></span> 2017 - 2020</p>
    <span class="tag green">Saas</span>
  </div>
</div>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/basecase/images/basecase-intro.jpg" type="" alt="BaseCase"  /></p>
<h4 id="about-basecase">About BaseCase</h4>
<p><strong>BaseCase</strong> is a no-code platform that allows the users to translate spreadsheets into interactive &amp; data-driven content, tailored for the healthcare and medical science business.</p>
<h4 id="my-role-at-basecase">My role at Basecase</h4>
<p>My collaboration began with assisting the Marketing team on the design of digital and physical brochures, along with the necessary images for the web and recurring social media campaigns. After expressing interest in building my own BaseCase apps, I became involved in the production of client-facing tools and responsible for the BaseCase Apps Library.</p>
<h4 id="the-demo-app-library">The Demo App Library</h4>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/basecase/images/demo-apps.jpg" type="" alt="BaseCase Demo App"  /></p>
<p>This library was a collection of tools that supported BaseCase documentation, illustrating everything from basic functionalities to complex features, along with product updates and use case tutorials. I was fully responsible for the ideation, design (or redesign), and implementation of these tools.</p>
<hr>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/basecase/images/bc-demo-apps-brief.svg" type="" alt="BC Demo Apps Brief"  /></p>
<hr>
<p><strong style="text-transform: uppercase">Process creating the tools</strong></p>
<div class="numbering">
  <div class="numbers">1</div><span class="numbers-label">Identifying the scope and usage of the demo based on brief</span>
</div>
<div class="numbering">
  <div class="numbers">2</div><span class="numbers-label">Create low-fi mockups in Sketch and put all the ideation into place</span>
</div>
<div class="numbering">
  <div class="numbers">3</div><span class="numbers-label">Create an imaginary healthcare brand, choosing colors, fonts and logo</span>
</div>
<div class="numbering">
  <div class="numbers">4</div><span class="numbers-label">Implement the design and functionalities using the BaseCase platform</span>
</div>
<div class="numbering">
  <div class="numbers">5</div><span class="numbers-label">Test the app internally ensuring its full performance</span>
</div>
<div class="numbering">
  <div class="numbers">6</div><span class="numbers-label">Send the tool to QA</span>
</div>
<hr>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/basecase/images/basecase-detailed-demo.png" type="" alt="BC Demo Apps"  /></p>
<p class="photo-footnote">Close-ups to some of the tools that made part of the Demo App Library</p>
<h4 id="marketing-assets">Marketing Assets</h4>
<p>To support BaseCase&rsquo;s online presence, we developed a series of images for marketing campaigns, ranging from new feature launches to company participation in fairs. I was also responsible for creating images for the BaseCase website, many of which are still live under each category on <a href="https://basecase.com/features" target="_blank">BaseCase Features<span class="fi" style="background-image: url(images/ext-link.svg)"></span></a> page.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/basecase/images/basecase-features.png" type="" alt="BaseCase Features"  /></p>
<p class="photo-footnote">Example of some of the Feature illustrations created for BaseCase's website</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>